<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured | Wei-Cheng Wang&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/featured/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Featured</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Featured</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/featured/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source-Free Model Transferability Assessment for Smart Surveillance via Randomly Initialized Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/wang-2025-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/wang-2025-source/</guid>
      <description>
  &lt;div class=&#34;pub-description&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;max-width:320;margin:0.2em 1.5em 0.2em 0em;float:left;&#34; class=&#34;pub-img&#34; &gt;
A fundamental challenge in deploying machine learning models is &#34;domain shift,&#34; where performance degrades when a model encounters data different from its training set. This problem is magnified by real-world operational constraints, specifically the &#34;source-free, unsupervised&#34; setting. &#34;Source-free&#34; means the original training data is inaccessible due to privacy or commercial confidentiality, while &#34;unsupervised&#34; means the new target domain has no ground-truth labels for evaluation. This dual constraint renders traditional model selection and adaptation methods ineffective.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
We designed and developed a principled transferability assessment framework that operates effectively under these demanding conditions. The core innovation is the use of Randomly Initialized Neural Networks (RINNs) as an unbiased, task-agnostic reference. Instead of relying on potentially biased features, our framework evaluates a pretrained model’s suitability by measuring the alignment of its learnt representation structure against the RINNs&#39; outputs on the target data. This comparison, quantified efficiently using minibatch Centered Kernel Alignment (CKA), provides a robust score to rank models without needing source data or target labels.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
The RINN-based framework was rigorously evaluated on multiple real-world surveillance datasets and downstream tasks, including object tagging, event classification, and anomaly detection. It consistently outperformed state-of-the-art baselines, demonstrating high Kendall&#39;s τ correlation between its predicted model ranking and the actual ground-truth performance ranking. This work provides a robust and practical solution for the critical first step of model adaptation in privacy-sensitive and data-limited systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
